Mary Braun

Pharmacist Assistant

Langhorne, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Mary-Braun/b4a5cbdf83b0f96a

Highly motivated, energetic and compassionate health care professional with experience in managed health care plans. Extensive medical knowledge and skills from twelve years' in the health care and pharmaceutical industry. Highly commended for providing significant contributions, both as an individual and as part of a team, along with demonstrating a strong work ethic and exceptional multitasking capability. Well-organized, reliable, and excellent communication skills.

- High Level Customer Service
- Medical Terminology
- Health Care Claims /Data Analysis
- · Analytical and Problem Solving
- Utilization Review/Management
- Health Insurance Care Plans
- Cisco Unified Communications
- Proprietary Pharmacy Systems
- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite
- Navinet Systems

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pharmacist Assistant

Philidor Rx Services - Hatboro, PA - October 2013 to November 2015

- Obtained written prescriptions and refill requests acquired through phone inquiries and faxes
- Verified patient information is complete and accurate through collaboration with professionals and computer systems
- · Answered telephones in a professional manner, while responding to questions or requests
- Assisted in streamlining communication with patient, insurance companies, pharmacists, nurses, and other healthcare-related parties
- Maintained precise notes and paperwork related to drug therapy and pharmacy care plan
- Established and maintained reputable relationships with physicians/healthcare practices
- Coordinated responses and resolutions with appropriate internal and external parties
- · Completed all tasks in a compliant manner

Patient Care Specialist

- Provided an exceptional level of customer service while performing prescription intakes, as a call center customer service representative
- Selected as Pharmacy Refill Campaign member by management team based on performance.
- Established and maintained professional rapport with patients, which matched the high level of service provided by the pharmacy
- Demonstrated compassion and professionalism, while obtaining patient demographics and personal health information
- Ensured HIPAA guide lines were followed in caring for patients.

- Answered inbound and placed outbound calls to patients, regarding their prescriptions
- · Serviced existing accounts, obtained orders, and determined charges for requested products
- Collected customer demographics and accurately entered the information in to multiple computer-based applications
- Maintained correct and comprehensive documentation of all queries, in order to continuously improve the customer service experience
- Managed difficult and/or emotional customer situations in a prompt manner
- Solicited customer feedback in order to improve the overall experience

Marybraun27@gmail.com 267-736-5201

Case Management Assistant

Doylestown Hospital - Doylestown, PA - 2007 to 2013

- Lead coordinator in all phases of the appeal process
- Designed, created and updated multiple databases consisting of various types of appealed cases which are utilized by directors and officers within the organization
- · Researched, reviewed and corresponded with the Department of Public Welfare on Medicaid admissions
- Closely worked with a team of case managers and social workers assisting with utilization review, utilization management and discharge planning for a post-acute health care facility
- Collaborated with the billing department, interacted with providers and other medical professionals regarding billing and documentation polices, procedure and regulations
- Received and processed all health insurance determination letters of approvals, denials, downgrades and retrospective reviews on admissions
- Remained up to date with all insurance requirements, including the details of patient financial responsibilities, fee for service and managed care plans

Health Information Service Assistant

- Reviewed physician correspondence from dictation service and made appropriate edits as necessary
- Prepared reports for various Insurance Auditors
- Demonstrated knowledge of HIPAA Privacy and Security Regulations by appropriately handling patient's information
- Lead training and on boarding for new associates joining the Health Information Department
- Actively participated in the interview process of potential employees for the Health Information Department

Teacher Assistant - Special Ed

Council Rock School District/ Newtown Middle School - Newtown, PA - 2005 to 2007

Administrative Assistant

Council Rock School District - Newtown, PA - 2003 to 2005

Teacher

St Bede the Venerable School - Holland, PA - 1998 to 2003

After School Program)

Medical Secretary

Pennswood Village - Langhorne, PA - 1995 to 1996

Unit Clerk

St. Mary's Hospital - Langhorne, PA - 1989 to 1992

EDUCATION

Diploma in Teaching

Lower Moreland High School - Doylestown, PA

SKILLS

Microsoft Office (7 years), Excel (3 years), Outlook (10+ years), Medical Terminology (10+ years), Customer Service Rep (2 years), Ms Word (10+ years), Computer Skills (8 years), Data Entry (8 years), Filing (10+ years), Internet (10+ years), Team Player (8 years), Typing (10+ years)